My house in Hoang Hoa Tham is very deep in the alley
always. It is,
uh, number 17, 267 over two--
on 33 Hoang Hoa Tham street. So if everyone turns from the
Going down Hoang Hoa Tham street, you have to turn about three or four times
Just got to my house.
Well, my house is in-- it's in a row of houses, uh,
isolated.
Well, there are about six or seven houses here
sharing the same cool yard with trees planted
then planted flowers, then, well, there were lemon trees, jasmine and all.
Uh, and it's... It's actually, it's tiled,
That private tile makes it feel very private.
And every time I go into the mold-- into the mold,
uh, isolated area,
oh, what a freshness and coolness that can be
be somewhere else
In this city of Hanoi, at least not on the street.
[laughs] Well, the location of my house is in the middle
The big one is Hoang Hoa Tham on top, Van Cao on his hand
left and Doi Can at the bottom. So because of that, I will know
range
Five ways to get to your house from, from those three roads, even
than. And this is the memory that only has memories
Only people who live here know how to get into the area
hey, uh, in three different ways like that.
Because... I know it's because of those times
I call, uh, technology drivers like Grab, Be, Xanh SM
Often they will not know which way to go to get into the house
me. They even go from the main street which is Hoang
always clear. And I will have to show them the way
what like. Well, on the map there's not only one way, well,
It's very accurate but it depends on [laughs] the so-called local knowledge of the people
the person who lives here. And they lived here for a very long time, uh,
much, they will know which way they can go and which way they can't
and which path will lead to where? Well, go out to Van Cao or Van Cao connects to the Team
In what part? Well,
Yes, the planning of Hanoi city
It will cut from Thuy Khue street or something
Go to Gioc Tam Da and go straight to your house.
And my house will probably lose at least half or more
The possibility is as high as eighty percent.
Well, luckily the road,
Well... Well, I'm quite sorry because I'm one
If there's a road like that, people actually won't need to call it a go
Go into the nooks and crannies to find your way into this area.
And in general, things, my memories and understandings
What I know about this area [laughs] won't be of any use anymore.
And in general, I feel quite regretful.
Because in addition to being a way in and out, it is also things,
a memory that, a, uh, memory that the people in the area
This they share with each other. Well, it creates a community
very strong. Because they will go on roads
they will know each other. And,
Um, the people who sell fish or chicken here are the ones
quite a lot. And, um, it's, and it's one
way to give their families, their-- their, um, closure
that connection. Right now, I don't know who will be in the future
nothing to each other, but there will probably still be topics to talk about
Uh,
When I was a kid, I moved here quite a long time ago.
Well, my family moved here when I...
about to give birth. So from the moment I was born, I lived there
Already. [laughs] Well, when I got a little older,
If something happens, my mother will usually tell me to go out
In that isolated area, right opposite there will be a grocery store.
I'll go out there to buy beer, buy eggs or everyone can take a walk,
Well, go to Lane 267 Hoang Hoa Tham, that will be it
spontaneity of the people here. So that would be, that would be the market
but all the people living in this Hoang Hoa Tham area and the whole alley
They went to the market there alone.
Uh, and those, uh, it's quite a source of income
Big with the sales people there because they live there.
They generally sell everything, vegetables, meat, fish.
Uh,
family-- they also trust each other very much.
The way my mother often comes out to get vegetables for her, I usually don't have to pay
money too. I just said, "Let Thanh's mother move later
Then my mother will move later. Because [laughs] it, it's like, yeah,
like a whole family and everyone, well, is willing to owe each other money.
Well, if we go one-- leave that Hoang Hoa Tham street and go
That high place has a very nice area. This is also a road where people
won't know. Well, it wouldn't-- I haven't seen anyone who isn't
This area knows the way. And it leads to a well.
So that well,
Well, now it has been converted into an area
And it is a space,
Well, people exercising is very cool. Because people imagine it is inside
That alley has a lot of trees and a lot of buildings around it
will not be exposed to the sun.
Living here is very comfortable. Everyone can go out there and have fun and hang around
There will also be a number of shops and a spontaneous market.
So the people who live on [laughs] the edge closer to Van Cao will go to the market to live
there.
Uh, um...
In addition, in this area there is also a national monument.
So this national monument will most likely become, well, a road surface or something like that
very close to the road. Uh,
It's a temple, it's a temple I don't remember the name of the temple
Everyone can come and check. In alley 267 Hoang Hoa Tham.
In addition, this is a land that is also...
Now it has rejuvenated a lot because it also has cafes.
Well, lots and lots of cafes and shops
Well, it's not just Vietnamese food restaurants like
porridge, but there are also ramen shops. It's done
coffee... There are also many types of coffee shops.
Garden coffee, coffee, uh,
study. Yes, but in here, it's probably famous
garden coffee. Because again, it's in this area
And there is a high possibility that in the future, many of those spaces will disappear.
Because when everyone opens the way, everyone will...
In general, the, the area-- the, those shops become streets
That tree will all fall down. And I'm so sorry
space ones
third place or spaces,
Well, reducing heat like that is actually inside the city
It's rare. And now when,
Well, let's clear out all those areas
Losing those things even more.
[background music]